# MICHAEL CHEN

Software Engineer | Full-Stack Developer | Marine Reservist

## **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I am a Software Engineer from General Assembly with a Bachelor's Degree in Biology and a Marine Corps reservist, with experience as an Emergency Medical Technician. A combination of all my experience provided a strong foundation to be reliable, passionate, and motivated.

## **SKILLS**

-HTML - Express -CSS - REACT

- Javascript - REST API

- Github - Postgre SQL - Node.js - Mongo DB

- Python

## **PROJECTS**

- **Spaceship Racer** - A two player game where each player controls a spaceship. First one to reach the other side five times wins with multiple difficulties that can be selected. HTML, CSS, Javascript.

https://chenmichael2.github.io/Spaceship-Racer/

- **Viral** A team project that uses MongoDB, API, and React to provide data on COVID statistics and user input vaccination sites with reviews and voting. https://viral-covid.herokuapp.com/
- **Organize** This app provides a simple to-do list made with React and MongoDB. Also provides authentication to tailor the list to specific users. https://organizeee-app.herokuapp.com/

## CONTACT

Email: chenmichael2012@gmail.com Mobile: (310) 961-7740 Linkedln: www.linkedin.com/in/chenmichael2 Github: https://github.com/chenmichael2

## PROFESSIONAL CAREER

## **General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive**

Engineering Fellow | Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

- Design and learn about coding skills like HTML, CSS, Javascript, and other tools.
- Work closely with fellow software engineers to create full-stack applications.
- Implement and maneuver data with multiple different types of tools to support application processes.

## **United States Marine Corps Reserves**

Expeditionary Airfield Technician | Aug 2018 - present

- Provide and lead maintenance actions on arresting gear, lighting, and airfield operations.
- Billets assigned include acting non-commissioned officer for foreign object debris, corrosion control prevention, and training and readiness section officer.
- Personal awards include National Defense Service Medal (2019) and Meritorious Mast (2021).

## **PRN Ambulance**

Emergency Medical Technician | Sep 2018 - Dec 2018

- Interfacility Transport EMT that transferred patients from hospital to hospital and worked well with a team of healthcare providers.
- Provided care and services to patients and provided proper documentation for each call given.

#### **ACADEMIC BACKGROUND**

## **General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive**

Certificate of Completion, Software Engineering | Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

- Topics covered include front-end web development, full-stack development, and front-end framework.

## University of California, Irvine

Bachelor of Science in Biological Sciences | Sep 2017 - Sep 2021

- Courses taken include general chemistry, organic chemistry, physiology, anatomy, biochemistry, and physics.

## **Southern California Regional Occupational Center**

Certificate of Competency | Sep 2015 - Jul 2017

- Occupational courses that include emergency medical technician, emergency first responder, intro to pharmacy tech, physical therapy aide, and personal fitness trainer.